Each country has them, national symbols that adorn postcards
And attracts tourists.
Sydney has its iconic opera house, Oslo its marble -covered opera
Milan the legendary La Scala.
And Sweden's 250-year-old cultural pride: the Royal Opera.
State Property Agency, SFV
which manages Sweden's cultural -historical heritage.
They must ensure that every village halt has a castle in fine condition.
Where one can go with the family when you have to find something
Because you do not endure being in the same apartment.
In total, SFV manages 4,000 buildings:
Citizens, castles, museums, theaters and state building memories.
Varberg's fortress, Kronoberg's castle ruin - you name it!
SFV is there and does a questionable job.
Unfortunately, many tenants do not seem to feel as good as the Royal Opera.
It is hardly possible to work there anymore.
It rains from time to time when the snow melts or it rains outside.
What a shame!
Every civilized country should have a national scene.
An important symbol for culture in this country.
I love a finely tuned opera, just last week I took part in
One of this year's cultural highlights: The set "Where is the sandwich?"
That was unbelievable!
Wow.
The whole show I wondered: Where is the sandwich?
Culture can really move one to other places.
When digging, you realize that the opera house has become pure horror experience.
And now I'm talking about state real estate.
Where were we?
Just that, flies in the crane, it's not good, no.
So instead of an iconic landmark, a dilapidated ghost house.
The Phantom has to leave the opera and walk on the city streets like an ordinary man.
And the opera is not alone in slowly breaking.
The Natural History Museum also seems to be severely neglected by SFV.
300 kilos of roof plaster that loosened.
The ceiling at the Natural History Museum in Stockholm
risks collapsing, and now they have to keep closed.
has increased, and because of the rental model they are plus on the rent.
All costs end up on the rent, even major local renovations.
The rent on the building can increase by 50 percent.
The increase will include:
Because they build a lift to the entrance.
Because according to the agreement with SFV, the Dramaten itself will pay for renovations.
It will be added on next year's rent.
The new elevator is double bad news for Dramaten.
Height rent, and so women must now share a lift with Örjan Ramberg again.
It is apparently tough.
As the opera "Where is my sandwich?"
You think you know where the sandwich is - and poff!
So they sow doubt.
Art can really ask the big questions.
Cost rent is not sustainable, and the government has realized this.
They will investigate a new rental model.
But it seems bark in another direction.
A review of the rental model has recently been conducted.
The investigation proposes a transition to market rent
And thus the same rental model for all properties with cultural activities.
Voldemort here ... sorry, he who must not be mentioned by name.
I haven't thought about that, I really hope
that the National Museum may retain its fine business.
You believe that the National Museum will continue to be the National Museum
In the National Museum's own premises?
Yes, that sounds reasonable.
But why should government institutions have to get on your knees
Because a state authority requires them on sky -high rents?
Like the state renovating itself.
A self -harm behavior.
Several stage art dealers come back to what they describe as
A KAFKA-ARTER MONOPOL GAME.
Tax money moves back and forth.
Through an authority, the state makes a new performance.
Then the state raises the rent through another authority
so the theater must take from the same money and return
to cover the rent increase.
Did you hang out?
Client, landlord, tenant, victim, perpetrator
Everyone involved turns out to be the state itself!
It was one and the same person all the time.
What a plot twist!
It was eerily like the end of the opera "Where is my sandwich?"
It emerged that the sandwich had been in the wardrobe all the time.